Michael J. Ryan

I have been working as a full-stack software developer, architect and in leadership roles specializing in web-facing applications in environments from dozens to millions of simultaneous users.

I would enjoy a role with the flexibility to design and implement great solutions that solve real issues. The past few years has been more focused on solutions utilizing React, Redux and Material UI (mui) using TypeScript on the front-end. Back-end services have been a combination of C# (ASP.Net/MVC) as well as Node.js. Database development has been a combination of SQL and NoSQL and search engines.

☑ resume@tracker1.dev

(480) 270-4509

Phoenix, AZ, USA

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/tracker1/

WORK EXPERIENCE

Yoh

Lead Software Developer

May 2023 - Aug 2023

- Fluent platform for First American Title company
- A multi-agency title process management and workflow application.
- Technologies include AWS DynamoDB, AWS Lambda, Node.js, GraphQL (Apollo), React, Material Design (mui).

Vaco

Senior Software Developer

Oct 2022 - Apr 2023

- Markletplace for HCA/HealthTrust
- Marketplace application for multiple client locations to access office and medical supplies to simplify their procurement process.
- Hands-on development and mentoring other developers.
- Leading UI refinement, refactor and establishing best practices.
- Front-end software included TypeScript, React, Redux, Material UI.
- Back-end API was in C# with a generated client via NSwag and using Azure hosted SQL Server. GitHub repository, CI/CD via Azure Devops and Azure infrastructure via Terraform.
- · Do Not Contact.

ServiceTitan

Staff Engineer II

Oct 2021 - Sept 2022

- Leadership, principal development and design of systems and architecture related to the Application Platform API services.
- Technologies include Kubernetes, Helm, .Net/C# 6, Node.js, React, MobX, Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL, Kafka, Identity Server and other systems were used.

Runbeck Election Services

Senior Software Developer

Jun 2018 - Oct 2021

- Online Petition Platform design and principal development.
- Authentication Management System design and principal development. Used with multiple products/applications.
- Petition Verification (VOCEM) design and front-end development for a web-based petition scanning and validation platform..

 Technologies include React, Redux, Material UI, JavaScript, Node, Koa, C# (.Net Core), SQL Server, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Redis, RabbitMQ, Azure DevOps CI/CD, Web Services, Docker, Kubernetes, Helm.

Berkadia

Senior Software Developer

Oct 2017 - May 2018

- Platform for marketing material generation and reuse from InDesign templates. Front-end in Angular, back-end in Node/Koa communicating with Adobe InDesign Server.
- InDesign CEP extension using React and ExtendScript.
- · Docker containerization.
- Local development team was laid off.

EmailAge

Senior Software Developer

Jan 2017 - Aug 2017

- UI/UX development and prototypes.
- · .Net application support.
- ETL pipelines for AWS DynamoDB and Lambda.
- Other technology used includes React, Redux, Material UI, JavaScript, Node, Express, C#, SQL Server, Cassandra, Docker, Elastic Beanstalk (Docker), DynamoDB.

Brooksource

Senior Architect Nov 2016 - Dec 2016

- Florida Blue
- Designed React UI projects (React, Material UI, Redux, JavaScript) with a Node/Express and Oracle back-end.
- Project scope reduced and team dismissed at end of year.

IntraEdge

Senior Developer

Sept 2015 - Oct 2016

- American Express
- Email marketing campaign management platform. Front-end in React; back-end in Node.js with MongoDB.
- Customer acquisition embedded tools for external integration using JavaScript, jQuery and Angular.

Inxsol

Senior Developer

May 2015 - Aug 2015

 Command Plan first responder training simulator. Front-end developed with Flash/Flex and ActionScript. Admin UI using JavaScript, jQuery and Bootstrap. Backends with C#, ASP.Net MVC and some Node for text-to-speach integration. Microsoft SQL Server database.

Collector Car Network

Software Architect

Jul 2014 - May 2015

- ClassicCars.com redesign and platform uplift.
- Design, collaborate and develop public-facing and internal applications for the ClassicCars.com website. Technologies include React, Material Design, Flux, SQL Server, RabbitMQ, Cassandra, Redux, ElasticSearch, Azure

GoDaddy

Software Developer III

Aug 2013 - Jul 2014

 Website Builder migration from ASP.Net MVC back-end with MS SQL Server to a Node backend with Redis and Cassandra. Front-end development using custom internal controls using jQuery.

EDUCATION

Peoria High School

June 1993

SKILLS

JavaScript ••••
Rust •••

C# • • • • • SQL • • • •

TypeScript ••••
React ••••

- TypeScript
- JavaScript
- ActionScript
- ExtendScript
- C#
- .Net
- .Net Core
- Adobe CEP
- React
- Redux
- Material UI
- ExtJS
- AngularJS
- Angular
- jQuery
- Bootstrap
- HTML5
- CSS3
- JSON
- Material Design
- REST
- RPC
- · Web Services
- NginX
- Node.js
- Express
- Koa
- · Visual Basic .Net
- ASP.Net WebForms
- ASP.Net MVC
- Classic ASP
- Windows Communication Foundation (WCF)
- · Cloudflare Pages
- · Cloudflare Workers
- RabbitMO
- Cassandra
- PostgreSQL
- ElasticSearch

- Azure Storage Tables
- · Azure Blob Storage
- Azure Cognitive Search
- AWS DynamoDB
- Redis
- SQLite
- MySQL
- Microsoft SQL Server
- · Stored Procedures
- Triggers
- Docker
- Containerization
- Kubernetes
- Helm
- Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- AWS Lambda
- AWS Elastic Beanstalk
- AWS Simple Storage Service (S3)
- Azure
- Azure DevOps
- Github
- · Github Workers
- CI/CD
- Windows
- Linux
- MacOS